Amit Khivesara

Khivi



Summary

Technical leader with 20 years of experience of leading enginering and data science teams to build business focussed solutions. I have been instrumental in transforming teams to the next stage of their maturity. Over the years I have build strong technical discipline within organizations. Based on my experience as a technical leader I authored a book on company culture.

Philosophy

Embrace Change	Change is inevitable	Be Lazy	Do more with less
Open Intent	Share before, not after	Roughly Right	Perfection is a myth
Be Inquisitive	Listen, Learn, Contribute	Feedback	Improve deployments
Outsource	Make oneself redundant	Measure Failure	Success travels easily

Management Skills

Communications	Open	Productivity	Extreme Programming
Mentor	Individuals	Process	Continuous Learning
Manage	Global Teams	Technical	Excellence

Computer Skills

Recent	Scala, Shell, C/C++	Past	Python, Java, Kernel
Dabble	Golang, JavaScript	Systems	Databases, Networking
Passable	Perl. PHP. Ruby	Platforms	Linux, OpenStack, Kubernetes

Experience

2019–Present Senior Director, AI Engineering, Target, Sunnyvale, California.

Leading the AI team for supply-chain and forecasting

- Leading global team responsible for AI strategies for Supply Chain & Demand Forecasting
- o Transformed research culture to business focussed

2017–2019 Director, Data Engineering, Target, Sunnyvale, California.

Leading the data science team for e-commerce search

- o Managed the engineering and data-science team for e-commerce search
- o Integrated a AI deep learning model into production
- o Built a continous delivery culture

2019–Present **Technical Advisor**, *iDataGenie*. 2016–Present **Technical Advisor**, *Verne Global*.

2016-Present **Technical Advisor**, Netcore.

2016–2017 **Head of Engineering**, Emissary.io, New York City, NY.

Emissary is a platform connecting sales professionals with former executives who have specific knowledge about their important sales targets.

- Transformed processes to an agile development methodology
- Hardened security practises
- O Developed a testing culture

2014–2016 Head of Engineering, Betterpath, New York City, NY.

Betterpath is a data driven health care startup focused on improving care for patients. I lead the engineering team.

- o Built and managed the engineering team
- o Setup outsourced QA team in Ukraine
- Obesigned and built reliable infrastructure

2012–2013 Senior Software Engineer, Konnect2, Madison, NJ.

Konnect2 is a financial services firm specializing in providing structured data exchange and algorithms for the global bond market. As one of the company's first employees, I took the product from an idea to deployment.

- Built feed handlers for bond trading market streams
- Scaled infrastructure
- Designed and implemented deployment pipelines

2008–2012 CTO, Mesh Capital, Jersey City, NJ.

Mesh Capital is a quantitative trading firm specializing in high-frequency trading. As the company's first employee I wrote the initial software that traded propriety capital

- o Built and managed the high-caliber engineering team
- o Primary responsible for Canada cash equities market
- Responsible to execution and delivery of strategic initiatives

2005–2008 **Technical Lead**, Roundbox, Florham Park, NJ.

Roundbox developed infrastructure to support mobile broadcast environments. I lead the global engineering team responsible for our server offerings.

- o Leading a distributed global team
- Build the world's only solution to support multiple broadcast standards (US and Europe).
- o Contributor to industry standards to interoperate with large vendors

2002–2005 Senior Software Engineering, Xebeo Communications, Iselin, NJ.

Xebeo was a successful company that built a high-speed carrier-grade MPLS router. UTStarcom bought Xebeo in May, 2003. I was leader within the software team and build and managed the network platform.

- o Primary engineering lead on platform
- o Architected the configuration and system datastore
- Responsible for the test automation framework

1996–2002 **Member of Technical Staff**, Bell Labs, Lucent Technologies, Murray Hill, NJ. DataBlitz is a high-performance, ACID, main-memory database system. I lead the team from a research prototype to worldwide deployment by Lucent within its flagship telecommunication products.

- o Deliver solutions with 5 nines reliability
- o Built database system 10 times read performance than any commercial database
- o Lead the team during organisation change to continue to deliver to customer

Education

- 1994–1996 MTech, Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, India.

 Masters in Computer Science and Engineering
- 1990–1994 **BTech**, *Indian Institute of Technology*, Bombay, India. Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering

Awards and Achievements

- 1999 **Awarded**, *Bell Labs*, Murray Hill, NJ. Bell Labs President's Silver Award
- 1994 Academic Distinction, GATE, 1994. All India Rank 9
- 1990 Academic Distinction, IIT JEE, 1990.

All India Rank 28

Publications

2015 Culture Seeds: Process, People and Companies.

Book available at http://a.co/iluqz2A

2020 Culture Seeds: Process, People and Software.

To be published

Interests

Privacy Technology and Society Music The Doors
Travel Small town America Enjoy Bourbon
Film Documentaries Food Korean